[{"question":"Coelom in cockroach is","a":"","b":"","c":"Pseudocel","d":"None  of these","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"","a":"16 pairs in two rows","b":"16 in two rows","c":"10 in one rows","d":"8 in one rows","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Read the following statements and answer the  (c) Lipid  (d) Glucose  6) It is made of a single thin layer of flattened cells with irregular boundaries.  & Astudent was given a sample of two tissues. He observed the under the microscope and  6) They are found in the walls of blood vess draws their figures as 1 and 2 given below.  Critical Thinking  (i) They are involved in forming a diffusion boundary ","a":"Squamous epithelium ","b":"Columnar epithelium","c":"Ciluted epithelium  ","d":"Compound epithelium","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Match the term given in colum-t with their fo given in column-1 and choose the correct option","a":"Exocrine gland. They help to stop  substances from leaking across a","b":"Endocrine gland II. Hormones are secreted directly into the fluid bathing the gland","c":"Tight junction  Tricky  neighbouring cells","d":"Adhering  IV. Secutes mucus, saliva thick due to sarwax, oil, milk and other coll products.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following can be absorbed by","a":"Glucose and amino acid  ","b":"Glucose and lipid","c":"Lipid  ","d":"Glucose","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Astudent was given a sample of two tissues. He observed the under the microscope and draws their figures as 1 and 2 given below.","a":"1: Columnar cells bearing cla  2: Unicellular glandular epithelium","b":"1: Cuboidal cells bearing cilia  2: Malticellular glandular epithelium","c":"1: Compound cells bearing cilia 2: Unicelistar glandular epithelium","d":"1: Columnar cells bearing cilia  2: Multicellular glandular epithelium","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Striated or voluntary muscle fibres are found i","a":"Langs","b":"Leg muscles","c":"Gallbladder","d":"Blood vessels","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The wall of heart is thick due to","a":"Puricardium","b":"Epicardium","c":"Myocardium","d":"Endocardium","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"\"Oxygen debris amount of nygen required for","a":"Muscle contraction","b":"Muscle realaxtion","c":"Muscle recovery","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Match the description given in columa-1 with their examples given in column-II and choose  the correct option","a":"respiratory negat      skin","b":"Organ which ac asunogenital doct  and opens into     urtes","c":"A small median chamber that is    Closa","d":"A triangular  structure which  joins the right ation and roceives blood though veria    Sinus ","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The non-excitable, variously shaped and found","a":"Dendrites","b":"Nil hodies","c":"Glial cells","d":"Schwann cell","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Consider the diagram and identity 1 to 5","a":"1-Pronotum, 2-Mesothorax, 3-Metathorax,  4-Tegmina, 5-Pleura","b":"1-Pronotum, 2-Mesothorax, 3-Metathorax,  4-Tegmina, 5-Sterna","c":") 1-Pronotum, 2-Mesothorax, 3-Metathorax,  4-Tegmina, 5-Anal cerci","d":"1-Pronotum, 2-Mesothorax, 3-Metathorax,  4-Tegmina, 5-Anal style","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Skeletal muscles show resemblance with visceral  muscles in which of the aspect?","a":"Shape of muscle fibres.","b":"Number of nuclei in muscle fibres.","c":"Presence of actin and myosin filaments.","d":"Presence of light and dark bands.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following ion is necessary for  the contraction of a muscle and nerve impulse  transmission?","a":"Na+","b":"K+","c":"Ca++","d":"None of these","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following statement(s) is/are correct about muscle tissue?","a":"Each muscle is made of many long, cylindrical  fibres arranged in parallel arrays.","b":"Muscle fibres contract (shorten) in response  to stimulation, then relax (lengthen) and return to their uncontracted state in a coordinated fashion.","c":"Muscles play an active role in all movements  of the body.","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"RBC are absent in:","a":"Cockroach","b":"Frog","c":"Cow","d":"Camel","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Vitamin K is required for.","a":"Formation of thromboplastin","b":"Synthesis of prothrombin","c":"Conversion of fibrinogen to fibrin","d":"Conversion of prothrombin to thrombin","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which among the following is not a characteristic of yellow fibres of connective tissue?","a":"Presence of elastin","b":"Fewer in number","c":"Straight and branched","d":"Provide toughness and strength","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following types of connective  tissue is mismatched with its matrix?","a":"Areolar-Loosely packed matrix of protein fibres","b":"Bone Mineralised matrix","c":"Cartilage-Highly vascular matrix","d":"Blood-Liquid matrix","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"In the given figure of areolar connective tissue, monoecious and both sexes have  by alphabets (1, 2, 3 & 4). Choose the answer in  well developed reproductive organs.  which these alphabets correctly match with the parts and cells they indicate.","a":"1-Adipocyte, 2-Collagen fibres, 3-Microfilament, 4-Mast cells","b":"1-Macrophage, 2-Collagen fibres,  3-Microfilament, 4-Mast cells","c":"1-Macrophage, 2-Collagen fibres,  3-Microtubule, 4-RBC","d":"1-Macrophage, 2-Fibroblast,  described by the given statements?  3-Collagen fibres, 4-Mast cells","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following is a purely motor nerve?","a":"Vagus","b":"Facial","c":"Abducens","d":"Trigeminal","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Sheath nuclei or Schwann cells and Nodes of  tissue and blood.  Ranvier are found in","a":"Neurons","b":"Osteoblasts","c":"Chondroblasts","d":"Gland cells","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Glisson's capsules are found in","a":"Kidney of frog","b":"Liver of mammals","c":"Heart of frog","d":"Cerebellum of rabbit","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following statement is not correct regarding connective tissues?","a":"They are classified into four types.","b":"They are most abundant and widely  Column-I  Column-II  distributed in the body of animals.","c":"They perform the function of linking and supporting the other tissues","d":"They include cartilage, bone, adipose tissue and blood.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following statement(s) is/are correct regarding cockroaches?   1: The body of the cockroach is segmented and divisible into three distinct regions head, thorax and abdomen  2: Blood vascular system is of closed type.  3:They are monoecious and both sexes have  by alphabets (1, 2, 3 & 4). Choose the answer in  well developed reproductive organs.  4: The development of P americana is  parts and cells they indicate.  paurometabolus, meaning there is development","a":"(i) and (ii)","b":"(ii) and (iii)","c":"(i) and (iv)","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Blood cells are formed in bone marrow. In a  process known as:","a":"Haemolysis","b":"Erythroblastosis","c":"Haemopoiesis","d":"None of these","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"The main difference between bone and cartilage  is of:","a":"Mineral salts","b":"Blood vessels","c":"Lymph vessels","d":"Haversian canals","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Nerve cells do not possess:","a":"Neurilemma","b":"Sarcolemma","c":"Dendrite","d":"Axon","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following type of tissue is being  described by the given statements?  1:They are named because of their special  21. Which of the following is a purely motor nerve? (a) Vagus (b) Facial  function of linking and supporting other tissues/organs of the body.  2:They include cartilage, bone, adipose tissue and blood  3:  They provide strength, elasticity and flexibility to the tissue.  4:They also secrete modified polysaccharides, which accumulate  (a) Kidney of frog (b) Liver of mammals  between cells and fibres and act as matrix.","a":"Epithelial tissue","b":"Connective tissue","c":"Muscle tissue","d":"Neural tissue","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Krause membrane or Z-line is a myofibril which  separates two adjacent:","a":"Sarcomeres","b":"H-zones","c":"I-bands","d":"A-bands","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Titin filament connects:","a":"Actin filaments to Z-line","b":"Myosin filaments to Z-line","c":"Actin filaments to myosin filaments","d":"Myosin filaments to M-line","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The figure below is related with mouth parts of cockroach. Identify A to E.","a":"A-Maxilla, B-Hypopharynx, C-Labium,  D-Mandible, E-Labrum","b":"A-Mandible, B-Labium, C-Maxilla, D-Labrum  E-Hypopharynx","c":"A-Labrum, B-Mandible, C-Hypopharynx  D-Maxilla, E-Labium","d":"A- Labium, B-Hypopharynx, C-Labrum D-Maxilla, E-Mandible","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"The efferent process of neuron is known as:","a":"Axon","b":"Dendrite","c":"Cyton","d":"Neurofibrillae","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following statement(s) is/are correct  35.  ,  ,  ,  about nervous system of cockroach? (i) It consists of a series of fused segmentally  Critical Thinking  arranged ganglia joined by paired longitudinal connectives on the ventral side. (ii) There are six ganglia lie in the thorax, and  three in the abdomen.  (iii) The sense organs are antennae, eyes, maxillary  pulps, labial pulps and anal cerci etc. (iv) Each eye consists of about 5000 hexagonal  (iii)  ommatidia.","a":"Both (i) and (iii)","b":"Only (ii)","c":"Both (i) and (iv)","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The inability to absorb be due to damage of w","a":"Ciliated columnar","b":"Simple columnar","c":"Simple squamous","d":"Simple cuboidal","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Tissue (interstitial) fluid would most likely be  found in:","a":"Loose connective tissue","b":"Nervous tissue","c":"Adipose tissue","d":"Bone tissue","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Conglobate gland is present in:","a":"Male cockraoch","b":"Female cockroach","c":"Earthworm","d":"Hydra","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which structure of man is similar to spiracle of  cockroach","a":"Nostril","b":"Bronchiole","c":"Lungs","d":"Alveoli","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The most important centre for the formation of  Ovariole  lymph is:","a":"Interstitial space","b":"Liver","c":"Pancreas","d":"Kidney","hint":"","correct":"b"}]